All right, you want to lose this last
five to 10, maybe 15 pounds, right? That
stubborn fat that doesn't seem to want
to go anywhere, whether it's in your
belly, on your hips, in your butt, on
your thighs. We're going to talk about
this. I first want to show you this book
right here. You've probably heard of
Suns Sue before. This is called The
Technology of War. You may have heard of
The Art of War. And I have a lot of
different editions of the art of war,
but there's this guy who translated
um SunSu's original text from the
original manuscript. He actually learned
Mandarin Chinese to translate this book
and he found that uh there's been a lot
of alterations over the years. He found
that the name of the book is not the art
of war because the translation really
wasn't the word art. art implies more
open-ended creativity whereas technology
implies an exact way of doing a certain
thing. So he actually found that the
actual name was the technology of war.
So anyway, this book is about a master
strategist um and what he did to win so
many wars. And a lot of the book is
about gaining advantages or creating
advantages so you can overcome an
opposition, a problem or an opponent
versus just using force or working
harder at something, doing the same
thing over and over and expecting a
different result. So we're going to
apply this to weight loss. So, we first
want to just kind of briefly mention
your disadvantages. Let's say that
you're menopausal, you're getting older,
your metabolism is slowing down, you
have chronic insulin resistance, you may
have atrophy in the muscles, which makes
it a lot more difficult to lose the
weight because um you need that muscle
to help with the burning of the fat. So,
I'm going to cover every single
advantage that you can use to overcome
this problem. But, I want to say
something. Many times when I talk to
people, they will tell me, "Well, I
already tried that. It didn't work."
Okay? And then you find out um the way
they were trying it wasn't quite right.
So, I'm going to talk about that as
well. And also some other times they
were doing it right. They just didn't
give it enough time. They didn't know
what normal was as far as losing weight.
They thought because my spouse loses
seven pounds a week and I only lose two
pounds or one pound per week, then that
means it's not working. In fact, if
you're losing over two pounds a week,
you're just losing water weight. It's
not actual fat. And an average person
over the age of 40, if they can lose one
pound a week, that's actually pretty
good. Also, you need to understand the
principle of it's not lose weight to get
healthy. It's get healthy first to then
be able to lose the weight. Because many
times in the process of getting healthy,
the body doesn't necessarily lose weight
first. It might get rid of the cravings,
get rid of your hunger, help build
muscle, but the body doesn't actually
naturally like to lose fat at all
because fat is a survival mechanism.
[snorts] So anyway, um you want to be
able to do something correctly long
enough and consistently enough so you
actually see results. It's kind of like
me with my guitar teacher. Um, he kept
insisting that I go really slow and I
really learn to repetition the patterns
of my fingers, right? Well, in my mind,
that's too boring. It's too slow. So, I
actually practice a little faster making
all sorts of mistakes and I never was
able to achieve where I really wanted to
go with that. So the key is first
knowing um what type of things you can
use to leverage this problem, right?
Your leverage have certain advantages to
leverage the disadvantages. Just like
you'd have like a crowbar that you apply
like a five pound pressure to lift a 500
pound rock on something, we want to do
the same thing with weight loss. So
let's first start with um doing the
ketogenic diet, right? Maybe your uh
carbohydrates just are not low enough.
You want to go as low to zero as far as
carbohydrates as you can. And I have a
video on that as well. It's called the
keto on steroids. I have another one. I
will put both links down below. But you
want to keep your carbs as low to zero
as possible. The other problem I see
with keto is you may be doing a dirty
version of keto, not the healthy
version. makes a big difference because
yes, lowering carbs will help you lose
weight, but having quality ingredients
and making sure those ingredients are
really healthy can actually help you
lose even more weight and get healthy at
the same time, which is what we're
trying to do. And also, just because
something on a label says it's keto
friendly, does not mean it's keto
friendly. Okay? And then, of course,
combining intermittent fasting, that is
a necessity. Okay? Had one person did
keto, but they didn't want to do
intermittent fasting. So, they were
basically eating um highfat, low carb,
keto snacks through the whole day
thinking that they're going to lose
weight. So, just because something is
keto doesn't mean you're going to lose
weight, especially if you're snacking or
eating between meals. Then, let's get
into the point of fasting. Intermittent
fasting. How long are you fasting for?
If you're at two meals a day, go to one
meal a day. Okay? If you're at one meal
a day, uh maybe you have to go to one
meal every other day. Also, periodic
prolonged fasting is really going to
help you. Let's say on the weekends you
do a 48 hour fast. Let's say once every
two weeks or every month you do a longer
fast, maybe even five days. I mean, that
right there usually will solve the
problem, especially doing a lot of diets
or have very severe insulin resistance.
However, that being said, I have some
people that do that and they still have
a problem. So, we're going to go through
some more things, too. So, we have doing
the healthy version of the ketogenic
diet. We have doing intermittent fasting
more aggressively.
And one thing I want to mention about
fasting, if you're doing prolonged
fasting and you don't feel good, what
that means is there's something not
right. You should feel wonderful when
you do fasting. I'm not talking about
when you first start out and you're
transitioning into the keto uh fuel. I'm
talking about when you're already
adapted, but you know, you feel tired,
you're hungry, something's not right. In
that case, you're probably going into it
with nutritional deficiencies. So, you
better be taking electrolytes, sea salt,
a good amount. You better be taking B
vitamins, vitamin D, maybe vitamin C,
and you may even need if you're doing
prolong fasting, a really good amino
acid uh product. So, that way you don't
have the calories with actual protein.
You just have the broken down amino
acids. So your body can use that to
fulfill whatever need that it's trying
to fulfill. And it's usually going into
fasting without having the right
nutrients. And many times it's just
adding more salt. But very minimally you
need at least one teaspoon, not a
heaping, but just a level teaspoon of
sea salt spread out through the day. You
put it in your water. That will usually
make you feel a lot better. So, those
two things right there will pretty much
handle for most people um any stubborn
weight. But I'm going to keep going. And
by the way, as I go through this, I will
put um a more detailed video on every
single topic that I'm talking about
because I don't want to make this video
two hours. Okay? So, we're kind of
isolating um what area you need to focus
on more by covering all of them. So,
then you can put more energy into that
advantage. Okay? Let's talk about
sleeping. Some people are sleeping but
they don't feel rested. They're not
waking up feeling rejuvenated. And I'm
talking about if you don't have a
quality of sleep, it's going to affect
your blood sugars. It's going to raise
cortisol. You should be able to sleep
and wake up and feel refreshed and have
energy through the day. If you don't
have energy, then we need to u look at
your sleep. I have a ton of videos on
this, but I'm going to put some down
below that are my most recent ones. But
as far as sleep goes, there's several
things that can uh help you sleep.
Number one, doing uh some type of
physical work around the house outside
primarily to get your mind off the
stress. So stress is one of the biggest
inhibitors of sleep. Doing a form of
exercise where you're really working one
or two muscle groups, but you're not
working the whole body, so you jack up
cortisol and your pulse rate so high
where it can't come down because a high
pulse rate could keep you up at night.
And then of course we have the
temperature being slightly cooler. The
other thing is your room. making sure
you don't have any extra light,
especially not watching your computer
screen right before bed or your cell
phone because that blue light can
inhibit melatonin. We also have a few uh
supplements you should be taking before
bed to help you sleep like vitamin D is
a good one, zinc is a good one and B1 is
a really good one. Even though B1 gives
you energy, but it won't prevent sleep.
It'll actually help you sleep because
sleep is an active thing. It's not a
passive thing. There's an there's like
the sleep pressure that pushes you into
these deep delta waves that you're going
through at night to feel rejuvenated.
It's it's a pressure that pushes you
into the REM sleep as well. Trying to
sleep an extra half hour or even an hour
a day will help you greatly. Uh even if
you have to take a nap. All right, next
topic. Gut issues. If you have gut
issues, it's going to be hard to lose
weight because um typically if someone
has a gut issue, they have a hard time
with fiber. So, they'll eat all these
vegetables and salad that I'm
recommending and then they end up like
feeling bloated or distended. That is
going to be a problem. So, if you have
gut issues, you might want to try more
carnivore ketogenic than the one with
the fiber or probiotics. I have a very
good video on that. We can't have this
bloating in your gut if you're going to
lose this extra 5 to 10 pounds. I just
want to touch on one patient that I had
who had a gut and every time he went on
a vacation down to Florida and later on
the beach, didn't even change his diet,
but the lowering of the stress, okay,
and the sleeping
helped his gut go down to I mean like he
was flat when he came back. It was
bizarre. So um that would be the stress
factor as well as the sleep factor. So
now let's bring up this topic of stress,
right? If you're going through stress um
it's going to be a big barrier, right?
Why? Because of cortisol. Cortisol can
jack up your blood sugars almost as much
as eating sugar. Because cortisol turns
even ketones and fats and protein into
sugar for that quick energy. That's why
even the hormone name cortisol, another
name for it is called glucocorticoids.
And this is why people when they take
synthetic cortisone or a steroid end up
gaining a lot of weight because of what
it does to um your blood sugars. Um in
fact, it can cause diabetes because it's
elevating your blood sugars. So, a
couple points with stress. Okay.
Physical work around the house, out in
the environment, long walks in nature,
vital. taking more B1 important. Also,
uh ashwagandha is a great herb and it
acts as an adaptogen. So, it helps you
tolerate stress much better. Vitamin D
will help lower your stress greatly.
But, um just from the topic of stress,
um when I've worked with people for many
many years, sometimes um those people
that have really stubborn weight are
just so darn serious. the intensity of
trying to lose weight and the stress of
it is keeping their adrenals revved up.
So, I told one lady, okay, who's doing
everything right, just to stop worrying
about losing weight, okay? Stop weighing
yourself on the scale. Just relax. Don't
try to lose weight so hard. Do
everything in your life that is
non-serious, okay? And um just keep a
real light attitude. I swear when she
came back the next week, that was the
only time she lost weight. That includes
stop watching the news, stop watching
things on the internet that rev up your
adrenals, have a relaxed, a carefree
attitude. All right, next topic,
pre-existing health conditions. Uh, so
many people are on medications, so many
people have health conditions. U, that's
the area that you need to address. I
have a video on every single possible
health problem that you might have. do a
search, find out how to address it
naturally and try to resolve that. If
you have some type of condition that's
inflammatory, you need a lot of vitamin
D, okay? And that can drop the
inflammation and drop the complications
of that problem, especially if it's an
arthritis, an autoimmune problem. And uh
that can help you lose weight right
there. Another barrier,
um the health of your liver. If you have
a fatty liver, okay, um you could be
doing things right now to speed up
removing that fat off your liver because
the more fat off the liver, the more
weight you're going to lose. All the fat
on your body has to go through the
liver. And if it's all gumped up with
fat or cerosis or inflammation, that's
going to slow down your progress. The
best thing to take for a fatty liver, in
addition to what I've talked about, like
keto and intermittent fasting, is to
take um TUDK as a supplement twice a
day. an empty stomach and choline a few
times a day. Both of those will help
speed up the dissolving of the fat and
it also will help uh manage your
cholesterol levels as well. In the food
that you eat, right, we want to eat food
that has energy in it. The more
processed something is, the more cooked
something is, the less life it's going
to give your body. So cruciferous
vegetables are just loaded with energy
and life. But let's say for example you
steam them, right? If you steam them,
some of them will be easier to digest.
If you ferment them, you enhance more
life to that vegetable. Why? Because now
we have all these microbes that actually
are giving you all these additional
benefits to that food. So that's giving
more life to the food, more life to your
body. The same thing with the food that
you eat. If it's grown on soils that are
just dirt, which means void of
microorganisms and you eat that food
that's grown on that, um, you're only
going to reach a certain level of
health. It's not going to be very high.
And so, when you really look at it, the
health of your body is dependent on the
fertility of that soil, which is
basically the density of microbes that
are mobilizing these minerals that are
not alive, like they're rocks. So you
need the microbes to mobilize that to
pull in the plant. So then the animal
eats that and you eat the animal and
you're eating something healthy. It'll
actually give you more health. All
right. What about bad genes? Right? You
have genes that are keep you fat. Well,
you got to pick your parents more wisely
next time. And I'm just being very
sarcastic, but there are things that you
can do that can help influence the
genes. It's called epigenetics. It means
above your genes. For example, a lot of
things I've already mentioned, fasting,
keto, reducing stress are all things to
help support these gene actions that you
want, right? And avoid the other ones.
But there's other things you can do.
These are called hermetic factors that
add a little bit of stress, not too
much, just a little bit to cause your
body to get stronger. And that would be,
of course, exercise, prolonged fasting,
but also cold therapy. Taking a cold
shower can actually stimulate brown fat
and increase your metabolism and help
you lose more weight. You can also do
the same thing with a sauna treatment
that can help you get the edge and give
you more advantage over this problem.
And so what we're trying to do is to
give you multiple advantages to actually
achieve the goal. Now another hidden
barrier which keeps you at a a certain
set point is chronic insulin resistance.
So, there's many things you can do to
improve that in addition to the things I
just said which will improve it. You can
take regular apple cider vinegar. It'll
make a big difference. Just with all
your water, you just add a teaspoon of
apple cider vinegar. And if you add
cinnamon in there or just take a
cinnamon as a capsule, that can also
help your blood sugar significantly as
well as make insulin more sensitive.
Bourberine is a very powerful herb that
can mimic metformin to help speed up the
results of insulin resistance. And of
course, exercise is another thing that
can help it. And vitamin D can help it.
There's many things on this topic. I've
done a more extensive video and I will
put it down below. All right, so now
let's talk about exercise. Here's the
thing. Exercise is responsible for like
15%
of this problem. Okay. But 15% could be
the difference between success or
failure. Diet makes up the majority of
the weight loss. Okay. Now, there's two
um types of fat primarily. You have the
visceral fat in the gut. Okay. And you
also have the superficial fat which is
just below the layer of skin, right? And
so women have more of a superficial fat
layer especially in the hips, thigh, and
buttocks. And that type of fat is a bit
less influenced by insulin resistance.
So if they do the usual things that I'm
mentioning with insulin resistance, they
don't normally see the significant
impact like they do mainly in their uh
midsection which is the visceral fat
which is more influenced with uh insulin
resistance. Okay. So that's why all
these other things will will help that.
In fact, that's easier to get rid of
than the superficial fat. But exercise
can be more of a tool for that than
anything else. Why? Because it's going
to build up more muscle mass to give you
more metabolism right off the bat,
especially if you have atrophy and
especially if you're postmenopausal.
So, the other thing about exercise is
that there's some mistakes that you can
make. Exercising over soreness. That's
really bad. That's overtraining. That'll
keep you from getting results. I had a
patient who exercised six hours a day,
seven days a week. That was the her
biggest problem. As soon as we reduced
it, boom, she lost weight. I had a
patient who was a guy who was exercising
seven days a week. I got him to work out
one day a week and he started to lose
weight. So overtraining is an important
thing. Don't ever exercise over
soreness. The other point is doing
enough exercise to create a stimulus to
make sure these muscles grow. Okay? And
so you want to use enough volume and
exercise to create that effect. How do
you know if you're doing it right? Well,
the next day you're sore. Not just the
next day, the next three to five to
seven days. That would be the right
amount of exercise. And that's how you
can judge it. And then you just let your
body going through that process. But
what I mean by soreness and I'm talking
about let's say your legs are sore but
your upper body is fine. So maybe the on
the other day is you're working the
upper body. So you kind of divide up the
body in maybe three different sections.
Maybe you're working your chest and your
shoulders one day and then your back and
your abs another day and then your legs
the next day. And that way you can
create soreness and then you want to let
your body fully recover. This way you're
doing it correctly and then you need to
do it consistently long enough to have
it work. So I want you to type down
below what you think you need to focus
primarily on on all the things I talked
about and then come back after you've
done it and report your progress. But
this will definitely work. If you
haven't seen my recent video on plateau,
that probably is another one to watch
too because I get more into the details
of the food. Check it out. I put it up
right here.